PASTOR: We're gathered
here in the sight of God
and in the presence of this company
to join together this man and this woman
in the bonds of holy matrimony.
If anyone can show just cause
why the two of them
should not be lawfully wed, let them speak
now or forever hold their peace.
Anyone?
Well, this is awkward.
I wasn't sure we'd get past this.
All right, go ahead and have a seat.
I want to read you some scriptures today.
No, not the traditional scriptures
I'm reading from Colossians
three, verses 12 and 17.
In the NIV version.
Therefore, as God's chosen
people, holy and dearly loved,
clothe yourselves with compassion,
kindness and humility,
gentleness and patience.
Bear with each other
and forgive one another
if any of you has a grievance
against someone,
forgive as the Lord forgave you,
and over all these virtues put on love,
which binds them together
in perfect unity.
Let the peace of Christ
rule in your hearts,
since as members of one body
you were called to peace
and be thankful.
Let the message of Christ dwell among you
richly as you teach and admonish one
another with all your wisdom through
psalms, hymns, and songs from the spirit.
Sing to God with gratitude in your hearts.
And whatever you do,
whether in word or deed, do it
all in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving
thanks of God the Father
through him.
Now, while dating,
you may have spent a lot of time
thinking about how you will dress
on this very day.
On your wedding day.
You may have thought what you need to wear
every single day,
like when you go to work
or when you're going out.
But did you think about how
you would dress throughout your marriage?
These verses
talk about how you need to dress
to respond each day in your relationship.
Verse
12 says, clothe yourself with compassion,
kindness, humility, gentleness and peace.
It doesn't take effort or intentionality
to be self-focused,
unforgiving, or impatient.
That comes naturally,
but it takes an active choice.
Time in the Bible, prayer, praise,
and thankfulness
to God to be able to put on kindness
when it's hard to put on humility
when you think you're right,
or dress with forgiveness
as generously as Jesus did,
and in everything do it is under the Lord.
Work, home,  professionally,
socially, all things as under the Lord.
Now, David
and Katrina have written their own vows.
And I'm going to hand this mic to...
it looks like Katrina first.
KATRINA: My dearest, David,
I love you so incredibly much.
From the first moment I heard your bright
laughter and witnessed your sweet smile.
I just knew you were someone special.
All it took was one video call
two years ago.
To make me fall in love with who you are.
Since the day we've met,
you've always held
a special place in my heart and mind.
At last we’re here in our wedding day.
And I'm so happy
to be marrying my loving cherished soul mate.
As your wife,
I vow to always be by your side in both
the good times and bad.
I promise to hold and comfort
you whenever you're sad and jump around
with you when you're happy.
I promise to care for you when you're sick
and be a source of encouragement
when life gets hard.
I promise to hold your heart tenderly,
being gentle and caring to you always.
Pray that we seek God
and always keep him
centered in our relationship
so that we can
not only keep strong faith for ourselves,
but also raise children together
who love and follow Jesus.
To my soulmate, best friend
and now my husband.
I love you, David.
Always, and forever.
DAVID: Katrina,
I've always had an image in my mind
of what the girl of my dreams would be.
I knew that she would be someone kind,
someone beautiful,
someone funny, unique and sweet.
The girl of my dreams
would bring endless joy to my life.
Even when things were difficult.
She would be someone that I
knew I could always trust and rely on.
Someone
that wouldn't just make life easier,
but make it a pleasure to live.
I'm so grateful
that God brought us together, because
when I met you,
I realized that you are better
than anything I ever could’ve dreamed of.
As your husband, I promise
I'll do my best to provide for you.
I promise to keep laughing with you,
to cry
with you, to support and protect you.
As your husband, I promise to be patient,
and kind, and understanding.
I promise to pray with you,
to walk side by side with you, and...
and that
in 50 years, I'll still hold your hands,
cherish your smile
and look into your eyes the exact same way
I'm looking at you right now.
As your husband,
I promise to love you for eternity.
PASTOR: Might as well hang on to that.
(audience giggles)
PASTOR: I gotta follow that!
David, do you take Katrina,
this woman,
to be your lawfully wedded wife,
to love her, comfort her, honor
and keep her in sickness and in health,
in sorrow and in joy to have
and to hold from this day forward
for richer, for poorer,
as long as you both shall live?
DAVID: I do.
PASTOR: Your turn...
Do you, Katrina, take this man
to be your lawful wedded husband,
to love him, comfort him, honor and
keep him in sickness,
and in health, in sorrow, and in joy
to have and to hold from this day
forward, for richer, for poorer
as long as you both shall live?
KATRINA: I do.
PASTOR: Okay. *Whew*
And we have rings?
David, take this ring and repeat after me:
With this ring...
DAVID: With this ring...
PASTOR: I thee wed.
DAVID: I thee wed.
PASTOR: And I
give you this ring...
DAVID: I give you this ring...
PASTOR: As a reminder that I will love...
DAVID: As a reminder that I will love...
PASTOR: Honor and cherish you...
DAVID: Honor and cherish you...
PASTOR: in all times, in all places...
DAVID: in all times, in all places...
PASTOR: And all ways, forever.
DAVID: And all ways, forever.
PASTOR: (whispering) Put it on her finger...
PASTOR: I give you this
ring as a symbol of my love...
DAVID: I give you this ring as a symbol of my love...
PASTOR: And all that I am...
DAVID: And all that I am...
PASTOR: And all that I have.
DAVID: And all that I have.
PASTOR: Katrina, take this ring and repeat after me:
With this ring...
KATRINA: With this ring...
PASTOR: I thee wed.
KATRINA: I thee wed.
PASTOR: I give you this ring as a reminder...
KATRINA: I give you this ring as a reminder...
PASTOR: that I will love, honor and cherish you.
KATRINA: that I will love, honor and cherish you.
PASTOR: In all times, in all places...
KATRINA: In all times, in all places...
PASTOR: in all ways, forever.
KATRINA: in all ways, forever.
PASTOR: I give you this ring...
KATRINA : I give you this ring...
PASTOR: as a symbol of my love.
KATRINA: as a symbol of my love.
PASTOR: And with all that I am...
KATRINA: ...with all that I am...
PASTOR: and all that I have.
KATRINA: ...all that I have.
PASTOR: Insomuch as
David and Katrina have consented together
in holy wedlock, and witnessed
the same before God, and in this company
have giving and pledged their faith each
to the other, having declared the same
by the giving and receiving of rings.
I pronounce that you are husband and wife,
those whom God has joined together
let no man put asunder.
Let us pray.
Heavenly Father, how appropriate
is to call you Father.
As you look down on your children,
what a joy
when we get to please You
and do as You desire.  And how disappointed
You can be when we fail
and we do fail, yet You still love us.
Today is no different.
These two are so perfectly paired.
I pray, Father,
that You bless them together as a family.
You cause them to grow together
and with You.
Let the path that they travel
as a family together.
Bless this house from this day forward.
In Your name we pray, Amen.
AUDIENCE: Amen.
PASTOR: You may kiss your bride!
(audience cheers + applause)
PASTOR: Ladies and gentlemen,
it's my privilege to introduce to you:
Mr. and Mrs. West!
(audience cheers + applause)
ANNCR: Ladies and gentlemen, we ask you to join us
on the back patio
for an open bar and appetizers...